Guide to the William H. Walter and George W. Walter Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
William H. Walter and George W. Walter Papers,
1844-1912; 1957-1967.
Walter, William Henry
2 linear ft. (4 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1558
6915590
William H. Walter and his son, George W. Walter were mid to late 19th Century composers of devotional music that was used primarily in the Episcopal or Anglican faith. This collection primarily contains sheet music of hymns, canticles, and other forms of service music.
Biographical Note
William H. Walter was a composer, writer and musician born in Newark, NJ 1825 July 1 to James Hahn Walter and Mary Cheetham, the daughter of journalist, author and British radical, James Cheetham. William H. Walter served as organist and music director to St. John's Chapel and St. Paul's Church, in succession, from 1847-1856. In 1856 Walter was hired as the music director and organist for Trinity Church and Trinity Chapel where he remained until his retirement in 1869. Walter received an honorary doctorate in music from Columbia University in 1865.
The majority of William H. Walter's work is composed of hymns, canticles and other forms of service music.
William H. Walter died in 1893.
George W. Walter was a composer and musician born in New York City, NY 1851 December 16 to William H. Walter and Elizabeth Wooley Ham. George W. Walter moved to Washington D.C. in 1869 and there he received a doctorate in music from Columbian University. He went on to serve as the music director and temple organist for Ascension Church in Washington, D.C.
The majority of George W. Walter's work is composed of hymns, canticles and other forms of service music.
George W. Walter died in 1911.
Scope and Content
The collection primarily contains music manuscripts and music related publications. It also contains a bibliography and genealogical information compiled by David Palmer (grandson of George W. Walter) pertaining to James Cheetham (grandfather of William H. Walter), an early 19th Century author, journalist and political activist.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 3 series
Series I: William H. Walter, 1844-1903
Subseries I.1: Music Manuscripts, 1844-1885
Subseries I.2: Publications, 1854-1886
Subseries I.3: Business Accounts and Miscellaneous Papers, 1845-1866
Series II. George W. Walter, 1865-1913
Subseries II.1: Music Manuscripts, 1865-1913
Subseries II.2: Publications, 1875-1900
Subseries II.3: Miscellaneous, 1870-1873
Series III: David Palmer and James Cheetham, 1957-1967
Subjects
Cheetham, James, 1772-1810.; Palmer, David C., 1925-; Walter, George William.; Walter, William H. (William Henry), 1808-1846.; Communion service music.; Canticles.; Composers.; Divine office (Music).; Evening service music.; Morning service music.; Offertories (Music).; Sacred vocal music.; Scores.; Scorebooks.; Sheet Music.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Walter Family Gift.
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Walter, W.H. (1860). A manual of church music: containing a choice selection of chants and metrical tunes, designed for use in public and private worship
Walter, W.H. (1857). Selections of psalms, together with the canticles, occasional anthems, and proper psalms on certain days; pointed for chanting, with chants
Walter, W.H. (1886). Mass in C, or Communion service, with Latin and English words.
- Series I: William H. Walter, 1844-1903
  This series contains music manuscripts, publications, business accounts and other papers created by William H. Walter.
  - Subseries I.1: Music Manuscripts, 1844-1885
    This sub-series contains music manuscripts copied and written in the author's hand. Also contained are pieces copied by Walter, but not authored by him and organ books.
    - Service Music, 1844-1885
      - Mass in C, 1881 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        (Originally written in 1879 this book was recopied with corrections for George W. Walter. Includes notes and emendations by George W. Walter.)
      - Communion Service in A, 1862 March 26; 1875 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Organ copy. Includes performance dates, Benedictus and Angus Dei. Includes corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Communion Service in A, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Communion Service in A, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Vocal score copied on 1872 December 26 for George W. Walter.
      - Evening Service in A, 1856-1860 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Includes corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Evening Service in A: Bonum Est & Benedic Anima Mea, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Includes dates and locations where the piece was performed as well as corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Morning Service in A, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Tenor part. Includes a Jubilate Deo and dates and locations of performance as well as corrections by the author.)
      - Festal Service, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Benedic Anima Mea, 1885 June 23-27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (First full score. Includes notes from author.)
      - Benedic Anima Mea, 1885 July 27-1885 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Second full score.)
      - Benedic Anima Mea, in C, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bonum Est, 1885 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bonum Est in E Flat, 1885 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Cantante Domino and Deus Misereatur, 1863 24 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Cantante Domino and Deus Misereatur, in E Flat, 1863 24 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Author's Manuscript. Continuation of the Festal Service.)
      - Cantante Domino and Deus Misereatur, 1863 August 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (Includes dates and locations of performance.)
      - Cantante Domino and Deus Misereatur, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (This copy was presented to Reverend G.I. Tucker of the Chapel of the Holy Cross on 1879 November 18. Includes dates and locations of performance.)
      - Deus Misereatur, 1845 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Dona Nobis Pacem, 1866 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        (In Latin. From the 28th Movement of Mass in A. Written for a female quartetto.
      - Fugue, 1882 March 30, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Fugue in E Flat, 1848 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes notes, corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Fugue in D Minor and Fugue in C, 1848 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Fugue in G, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (From Exaltobo te Deus. For the organ.)
      - The Litany and Introits, 1872 July 23; 1873 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes The Great Litany, a Preces for Morning Prayer and an Introit, When I Awake I am Still With Thee, which was written for Frank Weyman, Esq. of Pittsburgh, PA.)
      - Magnificat, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Song of Mary. In Latin.)
      - Magnificat, 1885 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Song of Mary. In Latin and English. Includes notes, corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Nunc Dimittis and One Sweetly Solemn Thought, undated; 1893 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (The Song of Simeon, dismissal.)
      - Te Deum, 1851 October 2-November 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Original score. Includes corrections by the author.
      - Te Deum, 1885 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (This copy was presented to George W. Walter for his birthday. Includes dates and locations of performance as well as notes by the author.)
      - Te Deum, 1875 August 6-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes corrections by the author.)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Letter From William H. Walter to George W. Walter that accompanied a vocal score to Te Deum in E Flat.)
      - Te Deum, in E Flat, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes dates and locations of performance as well as corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Te Deum and Benedictus in F, 1851 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (For the Advent season. Includes dates and locations of performance.)
      - Te Deum and Benedictus, 1853 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes dates and locations of performance as well as notes, corrections and emendations by the author)
      - Te Deum and Jubilate, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Author's copy from Morning Service in A. This copy was presented to George W. Walter on his birthday. Includes notes by the author.)
      - Te Deum and Jubilate, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Author's copy from Festal Service in E Flat. This copy was presented to George W. Walter on his birthday. Includes notes by the author.)
      - Te Deum Laudamus, 1857 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Includes notes from author.)
      - Une Reverie du Passe, 1884 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (Copied for George W. Walter on 1885 July 31.)
      - Une Reverie du Passe, 1884 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Veni Creator, 1884 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        (In Latin.)
    - Hymns and Secular Music
      - The Dark: Where do the little chickens run?, 1876 August (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Festival March, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Written by J.N. Pychowski, arranged for four performers on two piano fortes by William H. Walter. First Piano Forte.)
      - Festival March, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Written by J.N. Pychowski, arranged for four performers on two piano fortes by William H. Walter. Second Piano Forte.)
      - The Graduate's Parting Hymn, 1877) (Box 1, Folder 4)
        As sung by Grammar School, Number 47 (12th Street) Class of 1877. Words by Ida Sutton, music by William H. Walter.)
      - Jesus Tender Shepherd, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Lullaby, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Mother's Picture on the Wall, 1882 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Composed for D.L. Wing, Esq., Editor of Coney Island Sunday Spray. Two copies.)
      - O Lord, Thou Hast Searched Me, 1873 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Anthem for tenor, treble, bass and alto.)
      - Our Native Land, 1865 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Two copies.)
      - Booklet of songs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
        (Includes Elizabeth, The Hawthorn: HOPE, Song, and an untitled piece all dedicated to Ms. Elizabeth W. Hamm.)
    - Miscellaneous Music Manuscripts
      (These manuscripts are copied by W.H. Walter, but are not composed or arranged by him.)
      - Canzonetta a Tre Vocci in onare della Sina Vergine Maria, 1883 17 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Unknown composer. In Italian. The date is the date that the music was copied by Walter.)
      - From the Depth I called on Thee, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Written by Dr.Tye.)
      - O Lord Increase My Faith, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Written by Gibbons.)
      - O Praise the Lord and Gloria Patri, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (O Praise the Lord adapted from Ronaldo del Mel by Dr. Aldrich. Gloria Patri is an excerpt from Blessed Are Those by Tallis.
      - Save Me, O God and O Lord My God, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Save Me, O God written by William Byrd from the 54th Psalm, verses 1-4. O Lord My God written by Palestrina from the 7th Psalm, verse 1.
      - Teach Me O Lord and Praise the Lord, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Teach Me O Lord written by Rogers from 119th Psalm, verses 33-36, 40. Praise the Lord written by Dr. Child.
      - Unto Thee O Lord and All The People That On Earth Do Dwell, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (Unto Thee O Lord written by Rich Faurant. All The People That On Earth Do Dwell written by Tallis.
      - Untitled, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
        (A piece of music written by Tallis and Felton.)
    - Organ Books
      - Organ Book, circa 1844-1859 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        (Includes music composed by George W. Walter dated 1859.)
      - Organ Book, circa 1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        (Used at Trinity Chapel. Includes dates that certain pieces were performed.)
      - Organ Book, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        (Used at Saint Paul's Church in Yonkers, NY.)
    - Music Journal, 1852-1883, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      (Journal contains service music, hymns, songs, and other compositions written by Walter through 1883. In 1903 George W. Walter made notes regarding a number of the pieces.)
  - Subseries I.2: Publications, 1854-1886
    This sub-series contains publications by William H. Walter, including books, sheet music, and pamphlets.
    - Services and Hymnals
      - Communion Service in A, Booklet, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Full score. (Two copies.)
      - Mass in C, Booklet, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Dedicated to Mr. George Simon)
      - Mass in C, Booklet, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Bass part from All Souls Church.)
      - Mass in C, Booklet, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Tenor part from All Souls Church.)
      - Mass in C, Booklet, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Alto part from All Souls Church.)
      - Evening Service, Booklet, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (From Walter in A. Author's manuscript. Includes Bonum Est and Benedic Anima Mea.)
      - Evening Service, Booklet, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (From Walter in A. (Two copies.))
      - Evening Service, Booklet, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (From Walter in A. Includes Bonum Est and Benedic Anima Mea.)
      - Plain Service for the Lenten Season, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (Includes Venite, Benedicite, Benedictus, Bonum Est, Deus Misereatur and Benedic Anima Mea set to Gregorian tones. (Two copies.))
      - Choral Hymns, Ancient and Modern, Booklet, 1862 July (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (English translations of German hymns compiled by William H. Walter. First part.)
      - Choral Hymns, Ancient and Modern, Booklet, 1862 July (Box 2, Folder 8)
        (English translations of German hymns compiled by William H. Walter. Fifth part. (Two copies.))
    - Anthems, Hymns, and Miscellaneous Service Music
      - Benedicite, omina opera Domini, Booklet, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Includes Kyrie. (Two copies.))
      - Benedictus Qui Venit, Booklet, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Quartette.)
      - The Christian Soldier's Easter Hymn, Sheet Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Written for Saint Luke's Cathedral, Portland, ME. (Two copies.))
      - Christmas Carol, Sheet Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - I Heard a Voice, Sheet Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Two copies)
      - Impromptu, Sheet Music, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Dedicated to Miss Susan Arden Babcock. Includes corrections by the author. Written for the Organ.)
      - Impromptu, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Dedicated to Miss Susan Arden Babcock. From Classic and Popular Voluntaries for the Organ series.)
      - In Whom Shall I Trust, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (By Mrs. Mary E. Kail and William H. Walter. Two copies.)
      - Jubilate Deo, Booklet, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        ((Two copies.))
      - Let Every Thing That Hath Breath, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Introit for Thanksgiving.)
      - Funeral March from Lieder Ohne Worte, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Written by Felix Mendelssohn, arranged for the organ by William H. Walter. From Classic and Popular Voluntaries for the Organ series.)
      - The Marvelous Work, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (From Haydn's Creation, arranged by William H. Walter. From Classic and Popular Voluntaries for the Organ series.)
      - O Come Hither, 1865 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Anthem from Psalm 46, 8-11 for tenor or treble solo and chorus.)
      - O Come Hither, Sheet Music, 1865 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Peace Anthem from Psalm 46, 8-11 for tenor or treble solo and chorus. Published by the author.)
      - O How Amiable, Sheet Music, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Anthem from Psalm 84 for a quartette. Two copies.)
      - Out of the Deep, Sheet Music, 1864 September 9-12 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Anthem from Psalm 70 for tenor and soprano with a full choir. Dedicated to H.N. Bartol, Esq. of Portland, ME.)
      - Praise the Lord, O Jerusalem, Sheet Music, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Abridged Thanksgiving Anthem.)
      - Sanctus-hosana, Sheet Music, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sing O Heavens, Sheet Music, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Christmas Anthem for country choirs written by William Jackson of Masham, England including a treble solo by William H. Walter. Two copies.)
      - Te Deum Laudamus, 1858 January (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Dedicated to Madison Ham, Esq. on 1858 February 18.)
      - Te Deum Laudamus in B Flat, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Unto Us a Child is Born, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Introit for Christmas.)
      - We'll Meet in Heaven at Last, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - When Through Life Unblest We Rove, Sheet Music, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        (Words by Thomas Moore, music by William H. Walter. Dedicated to Miss Louise G. Pethick.)
    - Books
      - Common Prayer with Ritual Song, Book, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - A Manual of Church Music: Containing a Choice Selection of Chants and Metrical Tunes, Designed for Use in Public and Private Worship, Book, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        (Please see the circulating copy.)
      - Songs for Children and the Childlike, Book, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        (A collection of songs written by J. Ireland Tucker and William H. Walter. Contains notes by William H. Walter.)
      - Walter's Lessons in Music, Book, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        (A short review of the book is adhered to the first page.)
      - The Welcome Hour: For Use in Singing Schools, Choirs, Social Circles, Musical Conventions, Glee Clubs, Conerts, Etc., Book, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        (A collection of songs compiled by S. Wesley Martin and William H. Walter. Contains notes by William H. Walter.)
  - Subseries I.3: Business Accounts and Miscellaneous Papers, 1845-1866
    This sub-series contains a ledger, an essay on descriptive music, notes on musical theory and the script for a musical.
    - Ledger and Journal, 1846 September 10-circa 1866 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (Contains sales accounts for W.H. Walter's music. Also contains notes on Organ repairs and additions and notes on musical theory.)
    - Note, 1866 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (Request to W.H. Walter to send sheet music.)
    - Descriptive Music, Essay, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Untitled, Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (Notes on the elementary music composition and scale.)
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (Notes on Dr. Bubsy's History of Music.
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (Notes on scale.)
    - Music Manuscript Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Adeline or The Lover's Ghost
      - Script, 1844 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - The Gypsies' Song, 1845 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        (From Adeline or The Lover's Ghost Act 2, Scene 4.)
      - Oh Happy Hour, circa 1845 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        (From Adeline or The Lover's Ghost Act 2, Scene 5. Written on the reverse of Cantante Domino, No. 5.)
- Series II. George W. Walter, 1865-1913
  This series contains music manuscripts, publications and other papers created by George W. Walter.
  - Subseries II.1: Music Manuscripts, 1865-1913
    This sub-series contains music manuscripts copied and written in the author's hand and organ books.
    - Service Music, Mass in A
      - Words and Plan of Mass in A, Booklet, 1865-1866 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (An accompanying booklet to Mass in A.
      - Movement No. I, 1866 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Kyrie Eleison and a note regarding voice and music parts.
      - Movement No. II, 1866 June 27 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Gloria in Excelsis Deo.)
      - Movement No. III, 1866 October 25 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Et in Terra Pax Homnibus.)
      - Movement No. IV, 1866 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Laudamus and Benedicimus.)
      - Movement No. V, 1866 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Domine, Fili, uni Genite.)
      - Movement No. VI, 1866 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Qui Tollis Peccata Mundi.)
      - Movement No. VII, 1866 November 28-29 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Includes Miserere Nobis.)
      - Movement No. VIII, 1867 January 7-19 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Movement No. III, 1866 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        (Dedicated to Dr. Madison Ham. Incorrect copy of the third movement, Et in Terra Pax Homnibus.)
    - Service Music
      - Benedictus, 1868 October 16, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Based on Luke Chapter 1, Verse 8. Dedicated to Horace V. Bartol, Esq. Includes corrections and emendations by the author that were made in 1872.)
      - Benedictus, 1875 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Vocal score. For male voices.)
      - Benedictus, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Benedictus, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Vocal score.)
      - Cantante Domino, 1872 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Elegy, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Gloria Patri in E Flat, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Gloria Patri, Filio, et Spiriti Sancto, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Original manuscript.)
      - Kyrie Eleison, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Miserere mei Deus, 1865 April (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Based on the 51st Psalm.)
      - Sanctus, 1866 November 9 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        (Dedicated to W.A.N. Diller. G.W. Walter uses the pseudonym G. Whillikens Squybobbulus for this piece.)
      - Six Chants for Mixed Quartette, 1875 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Te Deum No. 4 in B Flat, 1875 November 17-20 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        (For male voices. Dedicated to the choir of Ascension Church, W.C. Hill, Jm. Johnston and Wm. Shuster, Jr.)
      - Te Deum Laudamus in E Flat, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        (Dedicated to Josephine Starbuck.
      - Te Deum Laudamus No. 4, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Te Deum Laudamus No. 5, 1875 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Te Deum Laudamus, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Te Deum Laudamus and Gloria Patri in E Flat, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Venite, 1874 September 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        (For male voices.)
      - Venite Adoremus, 1875 16 November (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Venite Adoremus in E Flat, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hymns, Anthems and Secular Music
      - Air with Variations, 1865 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (For violin.)
      - Christ is Risen, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Easter anthem. For male voices.)
      - Christ Our Passover, 1874-1881 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Easter anthem.)
      - Christ Our Passover, 1890 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Easter anthem. Vocal score. Includes corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - The Disagreement with a Slight Alliance, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (A chant by G.W. Walter composed by layering a chant by Rev. William Felton and a chant by W.H. Walter.)
      - Fantasia, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Dedicated to Madison Ham, Esq. The Prisoner's Hope, Fisher's Hornpipe, and Yankee Doodle Amalgamated, Mashed and Mixed Up on the reverse.)
      - The Prisoner's Hope, Fisher's Hornpipe, and Yankee Doodle Amalgamated, Mashed and Mixed Up, 1866 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Fantasia on the reverse.)
      - Die Felsenmühle, 1874 July 3-8 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Overture from Carl Reissinger's Die Felsenmühle transcribed for organ by G.W. Walter.
      - Hark the Herald Angel Sing, 1879 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Author's manuscript. Includes notes, corrections and emendations by the author.)
      - Hark the Herald Angel Sing, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 16)